In the beginning there was Bombolini the fool, Bombolini the drunk, Bombolini the joke. In the end there was Bombolini
the mayor, Bombolini the hero, Bombolini the beautiful. In between is the secret of Santa Vittoria.
The Secret of Santa Vittoria is a comedy, drama,
war film directed by Stanley Kramer.
During World War II, Italian villagers hide their wine from the German army.
Italo Bombolini, played by Anthony Quinn.
Rosa, played by Anna Magnani.
Fabio, played by Giancarlo Giannini.
Caterina Malatesta, played by Virna Lisi.
Capt. von Prum, played by Hardy Krüger.
Feldwebel Zopf, played by Wolfgang Jansen.
The Secret of Santa Vittoria is a 1969 American war
film distributed by United Artists.
It was produced and directed by Stanley Kramer and co-produced by George
Glass from a screenplay by Ben Maddow and William Rose.
It was based on the best-selling 1966 novel by Robert Crichton.
The music score was by Ernest Gold and the cinematography by Giuseppe Rotunno.
The film stars Anthony Quinn, Anna Magnani, Virna
Lisi, Hardy Krüger, and Sergio Franchi.
It also features Renato Rascel, Giancarlo Giannini, and Eduardo Ciannelli;
with Valentina Cortese making an uncredited appearance.
It was shot almost entirely on location in Anticoli Corrado, Italy (near Rome).
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.